Up until now, you've been treating stock prices as a continuous time series.
到目前为止 我们都将股价当做连续的时间序列数据
For instance, the end of day data for stock includes a row for every day or does it?
例如 股票的结束日数据每天各占一行 实际上是这样吗？
Here's how Facebook traded over the month of May in 2017.
这是 2017 年 5 月的 Facebook 股价走势图
As you can see, there's these clumps of five samples and
可以看到 每五个样本凑成一块
then a gap and then another clump and so on.
然后有一个缺口 然后又是一个数据块 等等
Take a look at the calendar for that month each clump of
我们看看这个月的日历
five dates in the plot corresponds to a workweek.
每个数据块都对应工作日
These gaps are simply weekends when the market was closed.
这些缺口对应的是收盘后的周末
Two months later, it's July and we see a similar pattern,
两个月之后是 7 月 出现相似的规律
but here at the beginning,
但在开头
there seems to be a date missing,
似乎缺少了一个日期
its fourth of July a holiday in the United States.
这一天是美国的独立日
So, gaps in the data can result from weekends,
所以数据缺口可能是因为周末
holidays, and other reasons the market might be closed.
节假日或其他导致市场关闭的日期
You might be thinking why is this important?
你可能会疑问 为何这很重要？
After all, if we forget about these missing days,
毕竟如果我们忽略这些缺少数据的日期
the data is still continuous in terms of trading days.
从交易天数的角度来说 数据依然是连续的
Well, that's true if you treat the price data as
如果你将价格数据看做简单的序列
simple sequence and ignore the timestamps,
并忽略时间戳
then you don't need to worry about the gaps.
那么不需要担心这些缺口
Say, you're computing daily returns.
假设你要计算每日回报
Take the price on each day and subtract it from the price on the previous day.
用每天的价格减去前一天的价格
Well, previous trading day that is.
即前一个交易日
For more robust approach to trading,
如果追求更稳健的交易方式
you may not want to ignore the missing days.
最好不要忽略缺少的日期
Even if the market is closed,
即使市场关闭了
other events can occur that might influence stock prices when the market reopens.
其他事件可能会影响到开盘时的股价
For example, company announcements, news articles,
例如 企业宣告 新闻报道
geopolitical events, natural disasters,
地理政治事件 自然灾害
anything and everything can affect the stock price.
任何一个事件都可能会影响股价
The more time between two trading days,
两个交易日之间的期限越长
the bigger the window for things to happen.
越有可能发生突发事件
So, you could try to normalize returns by dividing
所以 你可以通过除以任何两个
the actual number of days between any two samples.
样本之间的实际天数 来标准化回报
This may work in certain applications,
这种做法在某些应用中可行
but can reduce the genuine large differences,
但是可能会降低实际上很巨大的差异
or you could just use that information about these irregular gaps
或者你可以尝试在做出交易决策时
between samples when trying to make trading decisions.
直接利用这些样本之间不规则缺口的信息
Okay, let's recap, weekends,
小结下
holidays, and other events can cause market to be closed on certain dates.
周末 节假日和其他事件可能会导致市场在某些日期关闭
These dates may be missing in stock market data,
这些日期在股市数据中可能会缺失
you can choose to ignore these gaps,
你可以选择忽略这些缺口
normalize for them, or identify and deal with them as needed.
标准化它们或根据需要去处理它们
Another kind of gap you should be aware of is the time between the market
需要注意的另一种缺口是
closes for the day and when it reopens the next day.
收盘和第二天开盘之间的时间
Markets often allow some additional trading during the pre and post market sessions.
市场通常允许在开盘前和收盘后进行交易
Few traders participate in these sessions,
少数交易者会在这段时间交易
so the volume is low,
所以成交量很低
but these transactions can still affect stock prices.
但是这些交易依然能影响股价
Moreover, when a stock is listed on multiple exchanges around the globe,
此外 当股票在多个证交所上市时
its price may be actually changing around the clock on another exchange.
它的股价可能会在另一个时间在另一个证交所发生变化
When a particular market opens for trading,
当某个市场开盘时
the price of that stock can be different from
该股票的价格可能与
the closing price on that market from the previous day.
该市场在前一天收盘时的价格不一样
Again, depending on how you are using the price information,
同样 根据你使用价格信息的方式
you may not need to worry about these differences,
你可能不需要关注这些差异
but they may give you an additional clue that you can use for trading.
但是这些差异可以提供额外的交易线索
A more significant case of missing values is
上市和合并等重大企业行为
produced by a major corporate action like listings and mergers.
会带来更明显的缺值情况
For instance, say you're analyzing stock data from the year 2000 to 2016,
例如 假设你要分析从 2000 年到 2016 年的股票数据
Google only IPOed in 2004,
Google 从2004 年才上市
there is no existence of the stock prior to that.
之前还没有这支股票
So, what do you do?
该怎么办？
If you absolutely need a value to work with,
如果必须要有一个值
you can backfill Google's opening price from its IPO date to
你可以使用相同的 OHLC 价
the beginning of your analysis period using the same price for open,
回填从 Google 上市日期到分析开始日期
high, low, and close.
之间的OHLC
Since no trading actually happened on these days,
由于这些日期没有发生实际交易
you can set volume to zero.
所以可以将成交量设为 0
But, this may not be necessary,
但是可能没必要这么做
and it can be misleading.
并且有误导性
So instead, you can maintain a list of valid ticker symbols that form
你还可以保留一个有效的股票代码列表
the universe of stocks you're considering and this list can change from day to day.
形成完整的股票历史记录 这个列表每天都有变化
A more bizarre case happens when a company is delisted from exchange.
更极端的情况是企业从证交所退市
Perhaps because they went bankrupt or got bought out entirely by private investors.
原因可能是破产了或被一家私有投资者完全收购了
Dell went private in 2013 by buying back all its public shares.
戴尔在 2013 年通过买回它的所有公开股票变成私有公司
No record of Dell stock exists from that point onwards.
从此以后 再也没有任何戴尔股票的记录了
If you held a share of Dell stock on that day it went private,
如果你在此日期持有戴尔股票 该股票将变成私有
it's not like you'd lost that investment,
并不是说你失去了投资金额
you would have been paid by Dell for that share.
戴尔会支付你的股份
So, it would be wrong to assume that the price dropped to zero.
所以认为价格降到 0 是不对的
One way to mitigate this is to fill the last known price on
一种修正方法是用最后一个已知股价填充
the stock forward till the end of your analysis period,
一直到你的分析期限结束的日期
or if you're simulating trades over that time period,
或者 如果你模拟这段期限的交易
you can force sell the stock on that date and
你可以强制在该日期卖出股票
remove Dell from the stock universe going forward.
并在之后的期限中从股票市场删除戴尔
How you ultimately deal with this misleading values will
最终如何处理这些有误导性的值
depend on exactly what you're trying to do with the data,
完全取决于你将如何处理数据
but completely ignoring them,
但是完全忽略它们
might not be the right choice.
可能不是正确的选择